Ales Loncar

Software Engineer / DevOps Practitioner | Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Helm, Ansible, Terraform, Jenkins, GitLab CI/CD

München, Bayem DE

http://loncar.net



With a strong technical background and two decades of experience spanning various client, server and cloud infrastructure technologies. I'm a Developer in the heart with DevOps in mind. I always leave code and processes in better shape than when I first encountered them (Boy Scout Rule). Proactive problem solver. A team player and passionate about working with talented teammates. I like to learn, experiment and utilise new technologies, concepts and procedures as appropriate to project requirements. I embrace Cloud Native, and I like to build software in a "You build it, you run it" manner.



WORK EXPERIENCE (7)

Infrastructure Engineer / DevOps Practitioner at Accenture

Sep 2018 - Current

https://www.accenture.com/

Linux/Unix environment and scripting languages (Bash, Perl) Go Docker Kubernetes RedHat OpenShift Helm Ansible Jenkins Nexus SonarQube Artifactory Prometheus Grafana Terraform Confluence / Jira / BitBucket OpenStack

With my prior knowledge of software engineering and systems, I am providing infrastructure expertise on a team to improve throughput and stability of applications which are running on OpenShift Container platform.

- Maintaining existing and future software services code and configuration
- Helping to implement and improving development CI/CD software pipeline
- Helping implement new technologies in development for future deployments
- Providing technical guidance, knowledge transfers and mentorship to peers as required

Senior Software Engineer / Software Development Lead at Catenate

Jul 2018 - Current

https://catenate.com/

Java Gradle Confluence / Jira / BitBucket GitLab Jenkins Ansible Jenkins Docker

Working closely with our client's technical leads and management to align software project and plan the work with the software development team. I actively teach, advise, mentor and train during pair programming, code reviews, tech talks, conference calls. Solving day to day problems, mostly not related to business requirements but instead focus on nonfunctional elements such as maintainability, manageability, scalability, reliability, testability, deployability, and security.

- Leading technical discussions and debate issues with the engineering team
- I also get my hands dirty cutting code and doing code reviews, meeting with clients, coordination and collaboration to inspiring the team and taking care of that there are no impediments in the projects
- Mentoring and training, pair programming
- Tech talks: Cloud Computing, Containers and Container orchestration, DevOps Mvths and Misconceptions, Vagrant, OpenShift

Software Engineer CAD/CAM at Etkon GmbH/Straumann Group

Feb 2016 - Jun 2018

http://www.straumann.com/

Perl Ansible GitLab CI Docker Kubernetes Go (golang) MySQL Redis Microservices

I am part of a Software Development Team in CAD/CAM department which is responsible for: * software solutions to automate CAD/CAM production processes * software solutions for mass processing data in 3D * database-driven production logistics processes * development of interfaces to various IT systems (web services and other protocols) and CNC machines for manufacturing * development of intranet applications to support the production workflow

- Develop new functionality and refactoring of existing functionality
- Processes implementation and improvement (optimization)
- Proactively learn and utilize new technologies, concepts, and procedures as appropriate to project requirements
- Code reviews
- Perceived mentor: training other developers, pair programming

Senior Developer at Travian Games GmbH

Mar 2013 - Jan 2016

http://www.traviangames.com



Acting as game / software developer in the Travian 5 Games department. Mostly involved in development of tools for Travian 5 game and building communication layers between Travian 5 game and 3rd party tools. Supported team migration from Gitorious to Stash.

- Agile software development process: sprint planning, user story estimations, retrospectives and daily scrum meetings
- Daily usage of Atlassian tools for more efficient development process
- Develop new functionality and refactoring of existing functionality
- Proactively learn and utilize new technologies, concepts, and procedures as appropriate to project requirements
- Processes implementation and improvement (optimisation)
- Codo rovious
- Perceived mentor: training other developers, pair programming

Senior Developer at Central European Media Enterprises

Jan 2011 - Feb 2013

http://www.cetv-net.com



Developer on numerous projects: Voyo, Common Content Platform, Smart TV development. Working closely with central and local teams developing, integrating and coordinating deployment of new features

- Voyo Video On Demand Platform (TVOD, AVOD, SVOD, EST, PPV, LIVE Streaming)
- CME Common Content Platform (Zend Framework)
- API's for connected Mobile, Smart TV and STB devices (JSON-RPC, REST)
- Android development (Phone, Tablet, STB)
- Modules for Wowza Media Server
- Video trans-coding workflow implementing Google Widevine DRM

Web / Mobile Developer at Kitio d.o.o.

Dec 2008 - Dec 2010

http://www.kitio.com



Developer on multiple web & mobile projects including creating socile mobile portal called iSPACE.

- Web & mobile application development (using PHP with Zend Framework, jQuery & Ajax UI, XHTML, CSS
- SMS publisher for iSpace portal
- Real-time SMS chat web interface

Web Developer at AV studio d.o.o.

Sep 2000 - Nov 2008

http://www.av-studio.si

ASP MSSQL JavaScript XHTML CSS

Developer on multiple web projects build on AV SiteKit (Content management system).

- Programming in ASP with Microsoft solutions
- Network and systems administration
- development and integration of AV SiteKit

VOLUNTEER

Developer/Administrator/Editor at RockOnNet

Sep 2002 - Sep 2013

http://www.rockonnet.com

PHP JavaScript MySQL Photography Apache Linux

RockOnNet is an online magazine for music enthusiasts. I've developed it in 2002 and it soon became an online think tank for young photographers and writers who wanted to share their thoughts about music. It is still alive and kicking to this day.

Proactively working as developer, administrator and editor of RockOnNet web magazine.

EDUCATION (2)

Dropout at Faculty of Computer and Information Science

1994 - 1999

High school diploma at Gimnazija Murska Sobota

1990 - 1994

AWARDS

Honorable Mention @ Izzivamo Ideje at Si.mobil

2010

4 - 10 place with Android application: KjeSeRoka. The results of the event 'Izzivamo Ideje' Results

LANGUAGES

 Slovenian
 English
 German

 Native speaker
 Fluent
 Fluent

INTERESTS

reading

photographyMy obsessesion withphotography gave a birth of an

online magazine RockOnNet

cooking/baking

Epic Fantasy R. A Salvatore
Drizzt Do'Urden

I am a fan of epic fantasy novels especially from R. A. Salvatore.